The Ugly Duckling and Me! is a family, animation,
comedy film directed by Michael Hegner.
The Hans Christian Anderson tale gets a new treatment, this time with a rat
trying to exploit the talents of a little ugly duckling for profit.
Ratso / Frank (voice), played by Morgan C. Jones.
Wesley (voice), played by Paul Tylak.
Phyllis (voice), played by Anna Nugent.
Stan (voice), played by Gary Hetzler.
Chickens (voice), played by Danna Davis.
Esmeralda (voice), played by Barbara Bergin.
The Ugly Duckling and Me!
is a 2006 animated comedy drama film directed by
Michael Hegner and Karsten Kiilerich.
Intended for a family audience, it is a modern adaptation of the 1843
fairy tale "The Ugly Duckling" by Hans Christian Andersen.
The Yorkshire Post described it as a "feel good" film for family audiences.
The film follows over a rat named Ratso who strives to become a famous showman.
His life changes when an egg falls out of its nest revealing an ugly duckling
with brushy grey wings, and he is forced to becomes a father.
It also won an award at the China International
Cartoon and Digital Art Festival.
The film initially premiered in Denmark on 6 April 2006.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending.